manchesterairport.co.uk 2019-07-30

# Privacy Policy | Manchester Airport

##  Overview / Introduction 

At Manchester Airports Group PLC and Manchester Airport Limited, safeguarding your personal information and handling your information in a compliant way is important to us. We understand and respect the importance of guarding your privacy and are committed to protecting your personal information.

This privacy notice covers the way we handle your personal information that we receive from both from yourself and from our trusted third parties, what your rights are and our contact details if you need some additional information or wish to make a complaint.

It informs you about the types of information we collect, why we collect it, what we use it for, what your rights are, including consent, and how to contact us. If you require any further assistance or clarification, contact us or our Data Protection Officer. The contact details are provided at the end of this notice.

##  Personal Information 

We collect your personal information to enable us to provide you with our goods and services. This includes, among others, information you provide when you use our websites and/or our services for:

  * Car park space – We collect information such as your name, email address, car registration and bank details. If you have already registered with us, we will only collect your email address and password for us to retrieve your information. This information will help us to correctly identify you, use your information to supply you with the products and service and keep records about your purchases. We do not store your full payment card detail as your payment is processed by our trusted third-party payment processor via a secure encrypted link. We will retain your information for four years after which your information will be deleted.

Lounges (Escape and 1903) –   We collect personal information such as your name, email address, contact number, flight details, reason for travel and payment details. If you have already registered with us, we will only collect your email address and password for us to retrieve your information. This information will help us to correctly identify you, use your information to supply you with the products and service and keep records about your purchases. We do not store your full payment card details as your payment is processed by our trusted third-party payment processor via a secure encrypted link. We will retain your information for four years after which your information will be deleted.

Fast Track Security and Passport Control – We collect personal information such as your name, email address, flight details, reason for travel and payment details. If you have already registered with us, we will only collect your email address and password for us to retrieve your information. This information will help us to correctly identify you, use your information to supply you with the products and service and keep records about your purchases. We do not store your full payment card details as your payment is processed by our trusted third-party payment processor via a secure encrypted link. We will retain your information for four years after which your information will be deleted.

Hotel - We collect personal information such as your name, email address, and payment details. If you select ‘Text Message Confirmation’, we will collect your mobile phone number. This information will help us to correctly identify you, use your information to supply you with the products and service and keep records about your purchases. We do not store your full payment card details as your payment is processed by our trusted third-party payment processor via a secure encrypted link. We will retain your information for four years after which your information will be deleted.

Holiday & Flights – We collect information such as your name, date of birth, company name, full address, telephone numbers, and payment details. This information will help us to correctly identify you, use your information to supply you with the products and service and keep records about your purchases. We do not store your full payment card details as your payment is processed by our trusted third-party payment processor via a secure encrypted link. We will retain your information for four years after which your information will be deleted.

Runway Visitors Park – We collect your personal information when you book a tour on our Runway area of our website. This includes booking tours to view Concorde and Nimrod, Flight Academy, Aviation and Transport Festival and Gift Voucher Purchases. This information will help us to correctly identify you, use your information to supply you with the products and service and keep records about your purchases. We do not store your full payment card details as your payment is processed by our trusted third-party payment processor via a secure encrypted link. We will retain your information for four years after which your information will be deleted.

PremiAir – We collect personal information such as name, date of birth, address, contact details, flight details, passport and visa details and other travel documents, special assistance requirements and payment details. This information will help us to correctly identify you, use your information to supply you with the products and service and keep records about your purchases. We do not store your full payment card details as your payment is processed by our trusted third-party payment processor via a secure encrypted link. Your details will be shared with government authorities for border control and aviation security purposes and with third parties if required for operational reasons. We will retain your information for four years after which your information will be deleted. Sensitive information such as passport and visa details will be deleted one month after travel.

  * We collect information such as your name, date of birth, company name, full address, telephone numbers, and payment details. This information will help us to correctly identify you, use your information to supply you with the products and service and keep records about your purchases. We do not store your full payment card details as your payment is processed by our trusted third-party payment processor via a secure encrypted link. We will retain your information for four years after which your information will be deleted.

  * Our travel money site is run by our third party, Travelex. We do not currently share any customer data with them nor do they share any customer data with us. We receive weekly sales data and sales by currency data on request. Please click [here](https://www.travelex.co.uk/privacy-policy/) for information on how Travelex handles your personal information.

  * We collect personal information such as your name, email address, contact number, and flight details. This information will help us to correctly identify you, use your information to supply you with the products and service and keep records about your purchases. We will retain your information for four years after which your information will be deleted.

  * Creating a New Account - We collect personal information such as your name, email address, and country of residence. This information will help us to set up an account for you and correctly identify you for you to gain access to our recruitment site.

Once access is gained, we collect information such as your education history, language spoken, geographic mobility, and your cv. This information will be used to create a candidate profile for you.

Job Application – We collect information such as information already provided when creating a new account and creating a profile. We also collect sensitive data such as your eligibility to work in the United Kingdom, age bracket, ethnic group and information on your disabilities, if any. Information on eligibility to work in the UK is used to determine whether you can work legally in the UK and information about your age, ethnicity and disability is used to track and satisfy our legal obligation to include and employ a diversified workforce.

We will retain your information for six months if you’re unsuccessful, and seven years after employment ends, after which your information will be deleted. Alternatively, you can click on ‘Delete Profile’ on the top right bar on the profile page of our job search website. This action will permanently delete the information we hold about you relating to your job search.

  * We collect information such as your full name, contact details including telephone number and full address, date and time of event relating to the complaint, the type of complaint and description of complaint. The information you provide will help us to correctly investigate your complaint and depending on whether you agreed on receiving a response, we will or will not send a response to you. We will retain your details on our records for two years after which we will then dispose of them.

  * We collect information such as your full name, email address, contact number, the type of feedback, terminal, the area within the airport which the feedback corresponds and relates to, your comments, date and time of incident, flight number (if known), and a booking reference, if feedback is related to Car Parking, Lounges or Fast Track. The information you provide will help us to correctly identify you and investigate any queries. It will also help us better understand your feedback.  We may also share your personal information with third parties to further investigate your feedback. We will retain your details on our records for three years after which we will delete your information.

  * When you request to receive updates on incoming and outgoing flights, we will collect your email address so that we can use it to provide the information as requested. We do not retain your personal information and will delete your email address as soon as the request is completed.

  * When you want to exercise your rights under GDPR, we may collect personally identifiable information for us to correctly identify you and respond to you. You would fill your personal information in a form and the information which you provide will be retained for a maximum of two years.

  * We will collect statistics about your use of our services, such as what sections of the website you visit and when you arrive at the airport to check-in at meet & greet. We may also collect information about how our website and services are performing. For example, each time you use our website we may automatically collect the following information:

    * technical information, including the type of mobile device you use, a unique device identifier, mobile network information, your mobile operating system, the type of mobile browser you use, time zone setting
    * details of your use of our website including, but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and other communication data and the resources that you access.
  * We will also collect information about you if you take part in any of our passenger surveys or competitions, sign-up for our newsletter, or otherwise get in touch with us.

  * Where you provide your email address we will be able to link any information you provide us with and other information we collect about you to help us build a profile about you and your interests.

We will use this profile to help improve our services and to keep you informed about exciting promotions, news, features and activities that we think would be of interest, and we will use your information to make sure we deliver this information to you at the best time, such as when you arrive at the airport.

We aim to create a tailored and personal experience for you to be able to self-manage your preferences and how we get in touch with marketing material. To help us with this, in every marketing email we send you can click on a link to provide us with further information about you and your preferences. All this information becomes part of your profile.

We also use CCTV at our airports for security reasons and to manage our airports, for example, CCTV footage helps us to monitor queues at our airports.  We may share CCTV footage with airlines that operate in the airports for security and monitoring of services and with law enforcement bodies.

  * The free WiFi service in our airport is provided by Virgin Media. When you sign up to use the WiFi in our airports, your personal information is collected by Manchester Airport. We will use your personal information to market our relevant products and services to you.

  * We collect your biometric data at Manchester Airport Terminal 3. The images are retained for a period of 24 hours and only shared with the police or immigration for national security purposes.

##  Special Categories of Data 

This refers to any sensitive data you may voluntarily provide when you send correspondences to us. This data may be used for legal purposes, to help understand and respond to you, or to meet our contractual obligations.

##  Media Centre 

We collect a lot of information from our interaction with the public. This can be via various media interactions such as Social Media, Community Relations, Outreach Sessions and General Correspondences.

  *   *   * Outreach Sessions – We organise outreach sessions in public places such as libraries and schools to provide information to the public and collect information from the public. Occasionally we collect personally identifiable information from members of the public who have specific enquiries which can only be resolved in our offices. The information collected will help us to investigate and or resolve your query. The information collected will be retained and deleted after two years.

  * General Correspondences – We may receive your personal information from any member of public who may be enquiring about an issue or incident which you may have been involved in. For example, a member of parliament may send us an enquiry relating to a member of his/her constituency. This letter may include the personally identifiable information of the person in question. The information collected will be processed for the purposes of responding to the query. If the query is received via email, the email data will be deleted two years after the date it was received. Paper requests or correspondences which contain your personal information shall be securely disposed of after three years.

##  Sharing Your Personal Data 

We may use the personal information we collect about you to create statistics and anonymised information to share with third parties including ad networks, search engines and analytics providers.

We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries. For more information about our group of companies please click [here](https://www.magairports.com/) to visit our corporate website.

We will always make it clear if your personal information is going to be shared with a third party for marketing.

We may share your personal information if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal information to comply with any legal obligation, court or police request, or to enforce or apply our [terms of use](https://www.magairports.com/site-tools/terms-conditions/) or [terms and conditions of sale](https://www.manchesterairport.co.uk/terms-and-conditions/) and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Manchester Airport Limited and the Manchester Airport Group PLC, our customers, or others.

If you have booked to use the PremiAir private terminal, your details will be shared with government authorities for border control and aviation security purposes and with third parties if required for operational reasons.

##  Partners and Third Parties 

Some of our services are provided by third parties on our behalf. In these instances, your personal information will be collected by our partner and then passed to us. For more information about the services provided by our third parties, please see our Third Parties section of this notice.

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. We do not have any control over other websites and we are not responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not covered by this privacy notice. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy policy applicable to the website in question.

  * We use several third parties to provide the goods and services that you require. For a list of our third parties, please click [here](https://www.manchesterairport.co.uk/help/third-party-contacts/).

Dixons – When you reserve a technology item on our website, we share your personal information with Dixons. This will help them to easily identify your reservation, reserve it and hand it over to you when you arrive at their store in the duty-free area of the airport. If you would like to know how Dixons treats your personal data, please click [here](http://www.dixonsretail.com/site-services/privacy/).

World Duty Free – When you reserve a World Duty Free item on our website, we share your personal information with World Duty Free. This will help them to easily identify you and provide the required goods and services to you. If you would like to know how World Duty Free handles your personal data, please click [here](http://uk.worlddutyfree.com/ukm_en/privacy-and-cookie-policy/).

ADVAM – When you book or reserve car park, lounges & fast track (passport and security) on our websites, we use ADVAM to manage your booking. Your information which you enter may also be visible to ADVAM. If you would like to know how ADVAM handles your personal data, please click [here](https://advam.com/privacy/privacy-policy/).

AIMS – We use AIMS to deliver our loyalty and customer experience solutions. When you book a space in any of our lounges, AIMS receives your data. This will help them to handle your lounge bookings and post booking journeys. For an idea of how AIMS handle your personal data, please click [here](https://www.aimslounge.com/beta-site/privacypolicy.htm).

Park-IT – We use Park-IT to provide our parking solution. When you book for parking space on our websites, Park-IT receives your data and handles the meet & greet parking bookings and post journey bookings. You can read Park-IT’s privacy notice by visiting their website [here](https://park-it-solutions.com/).

Scheidt & Bachmann (S&B) – When you book for parking space on our websites, S&B receives your data. S&B uses this data to identify you when you arrive at our barriers. For more information on how S&B handles your personal data, please click [here](https://www.scheidt-bachmann.de/en/data-privacy/).

Vibe – Vibe handles the travel area of our website. This includes booking flights, hotels and holidays. Vibe shares the personal information that they collect about you with us. For more information on how Vibe treats your personal data, please click [here](https://fly.manchesterairport.co.uk/travel/privacy-policy/).

Virgin Media -  Virgin Media WiFi handles our free WiFi service within our three airports. When you sign up to use our free WiFi, Virgin Media has access to the personal information which you use to sign up. For more information on how Virgin Media treats your personal information, please click [here](http://www.virginmedia.com/shop/the-legal-stuff/privacy-policy.html/).

  * Salesforce – Customer Relationship Management (CRM) used by our online services to hold customer details

Oracle BI (full transaction data) – Used for financial reporting

Mastercard – Handles our card payment transactions. You can view their privacy notice [here](https://www.mastercard.co.uk/en-gb/about-mastercard/what-we-do/privacy.html/).

PayPal – Handles payment transactions. You can view their privacy notice [here](https://www.paypal.com/uk/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full/).

  * When you use our websites, we share your anonymized data with our trusted third parties. We use Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager, IGO and Quantserv to track customer behaviour on our websites. HotJar captures web sessions for us to understand customer behaviour.

We also share anonymised data with Facebook and Google. The data shared cannot be viewed by a natural person. They are encrypted data which Facebook and Google may use to provide tailored services to you whilst you use their websites. For a view of how Facebook and Google use your personal data to match you with the right products and services, please check out their websites.

Please click [here](https://www.manchesterairport.co.uk/help/third-party-contacts/) to get a list of our third parties and affiliates.

##  Your Rights 

The General Data Protection Regulation gives you certain rights relating to the personal data that is processed by Manchester Airport. Find below the list of rights and what they mean. If you wish to exercise any of these rights, please contact our Data Protection Officer at our address below, or alternatively you can send an email to [DPO@magairports.com](mailto:DPO@magairports.com). You will receive an acknowledgement within three working days of sending your request and a full response within twenty-eight days of receiving all the relevant information required to handle your request.

  * Right of Access – You have the right to access all the personal information and supplementary information that we hold about you. This will allow you to be aware of and verify the lawfulness of us processing your information. We would respond to your subject access request within twenty-eight days. Please use this form [here](https://live-webadmin-media.s3.amazonaws.com/media/4165/subject-access-request.docx) or contact our Data Protection Officer at the address at the end of this notice, if you wish to make a subject access request.

  * Right to Rectify – You have the right to request for your inaccurate personal information to be rectified or completed if it is incomplete.

  * Right to Erasure – We automatically delete your information from our records when the retention period has lapsed. Prior to us automatically deleting your information, you have the right to request for your information to be deleted and have your personal information erased from our records, if there is no reason for us to hold your information.

  * Right to Restrict Processing -  You have the right to object to the processing of your information if it causes unwarranted and substantial damage or distress. If it does, you have the right to require us to stop (or not to begin) the processing in question. This right does not automatically trigger the right to erasure. You will have to request for your information to be fully deleted from our records if you wish to exercise your right to erasure.

  * Right to Data Portability – You have the right to obtain and reuse your personal information which we hold. This compelling will allow you to move, copy or transfer personal information easily from one IT environment to another in a safe and secure way.

  * Right to Object – You have the right to object to us using your personal information for direct marketing and profiling. This right can be exercised at any point in time, whether at the point where we collect your personal information, or after we already have already collected your personal information. If you want to object to us processing your personal information, please contact the Data Protection Officer at our address at the end of this notice. Alternatively, you can also exercise the right at any time by clicking ‘unsubscribe’ in any marketing email.

  * Right to Lodge a Complaint – You have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office [here](https://ico.org.uk/concerns/), if you feel that our processing of your personal information infringes on your rights per the requirements of the General Data Protection Regulation. We advise that you contact our Data Protection Officer at our address at the end of this notice to attempt to resolve it before escalating your complaint to the regulators.

  * Right to Withdraw Consent – You have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. Your withdrawal of consent shall not affect the lawfulness of processing of your data before the withdrawal. You can withdraw consent by contacting our Data Protection Officer at the address below, or alternatively, you can click ‘unsubscribe’ in any marketing email to withdraw consent in relation to marketing.

##  Security and Data Storage 

All the personal information we collect about you is stored by us or our service providers on our behalf. We transfer your personal information outside the EEA only when necessary. We take steps to ensure your personal information is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.  Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our websites, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential.  We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

To provide you with the products and services and our website, we may need to store or transfer your personal information to countries outside the European Economic Area. Our list of third parties who may receive your personal information can be found [here](https://www.manchesterairport.co.uk/help/third-party-contacts/).

##  Cookies 

We use cookies to help us better understand user behaviour, tell us which parts of our websites people have visited, and facilitate and measure the effectiveness of advertisements and web searches. For more information about our cookies policy, please click [here](https://www.manchesterairport.co.uk/cookie-policy/).

##  Data Protection Officer 

Our Data Protection Office is located at our Head Office, Olympic House, Manchester Airport, Manchester, M90 1QX. If you wish to contact our data protection officer regarding the information in this privacy notice, or any query relating to your personal information, please contact her at:

Charlotte Lewendon

Data Protection Officer

Manchester Airports Group (MAG)

Olympic House

3rd Floor

Manchester Airport

M90 1QX

E:[DPO@magairports.com](mailto:DPO@magairports.com)

Or alternatively you can get in touch with us via our feedback area [here](https://www.manchesterairport.co.uk/help/feedback-form/).

##  Changes to this Privacy Notice 

We may change our privacy notice at any time and without notice, so we recommend that you visit this page occasionally to check what has changed. This policy was last updated in May 2018 and will be reviewed again in May 2019.

##  Contact Details 

Manchester Airports Group PLC

Olympic House

Manchester Airport

Manchester

M90 1QX

Manchester Airport

Olympic House

Manchester Airport

Manchester

M90 1QX
